

# MIRIAM BADE Software Engineer

- **9** Great Falls, MT
- **\** +14064755206

☑yukinomiriam@gmail.com

Miriambade.com/MiriamBade/

#### Introduction

Stay-at-home mom of a 10 month old baby girl looking forward to go back to the working life as a Software Developer.

I have 9 years of experience working in Java Enterprise Projects performing activities of: analysis, development, testing, deployment, and software debugging as well as production support.

### Skills

Back end development

Use of Java, XML, C#, Spring, Struts, Hibernate, Abator, EJB, SVN, SOAP., Maven.

Front end development

Use of jQuery, AJAX, JSON, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSP, JSF.

Databases

Oracle, MySQL, SQL, JDBC, PL/SQL.

**Production Support** 

Meetings with the user in case of production issues, tracking of reported issues using JIRA. Development of enhancements and defects fixes per release.

Others

DevOps, SDLC, Agile, UML, BPMN, Storyboarding,

### Certifications

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer

### Work experience

# 2016-06 - Solutions Engineer

Deloitte LLP

Solutions Engineer-Bismarck, ND

- Collaborated in a team-based, Agile environment to accomplish objectives in a measured and open manner.
- Performed 4 onsite training sessions for client-side developers to maximize productivity.
- Collaborated with clients from concept through final delivery of 3 enhancements.
- Coordinated with offshore team to confirm, develop and test requirements and defects on daily calls.
- Participated in requirements gathering and design development meetings.
- Performed troubleshooting, diagnostics and analysis to uncover root malfunctions solving at least 1 issue per day.
- Reviewed code and debugged errors to improve performance.
- Consistently met deadlines and requirements for all production work orders.
- Completed at least 3 low-level defects for every biweekly release and 2 high-level defects and enhancements per monthly release.

## 2012-12 - IT Consultant

2016-05 Deloitte Consulting Mexico

IT Consultant Helena, MT

- Collaborated in a team-based, Agile environment to accomplish objectives in a measured and open manner.
- Performed production support activities resolving at least 3 issues per week. This included analysis and resolution of production issues for two Web Enterprise Applications.
- Resolved production issues in less than 24 hours of their occurrence.
- Delivered 14 assigned enhancements and defects on-time and to a high level of quality during the construction phase for the new release. This included the steps of analysis, design, development and unit testing.
- Communicated daily progress to track lead indicating progress made against assignments.

# 2012-04 - **Java Developer** 2012-11 **Quality & Knowl**

Quality & Knowledge on IT Services - Mexico City, Mexico

- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Consulted with customers to gather requirements and discuss design choices.
- Developed designs to meet specific requirements such as quickloading sites with layouts.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.

#### 2009-08 - **Java Developer** 2012-03 **LightSoft - Mexi**

LightSoft - Mexico City, Mexico

- Developed robust Java code for Web applications.
- Developed Java code for 4 Blackberry applications.
- Collaborated with clients from concept through final delivery of a requirement.
- Directed onsite training for business users.

# 2008-03 - Junior Java Developer

2009-07 iSmarts - Mexico City, Mexico

- Developed requirements along with senior developers.
- Provided documentation for new requirements.
- Documented customer requirements and project plans.
- Created documentation using UML and BPMN.

# Languages

- English (Professional)Spanish (Native)

### Interests -

- PhotographyGraphic DesignCooking

# **Education**

2003 - 2006 B.Sc Computer Science and Engineering

Universidad ETAC - Mexico City, Mexico